DAN KLEIN: So there's a lot of kinds
of CSPs In general, the CSPs we're
going to see in this course are CSPs
that have discrete variables.
Usually they're not only discrete,
they also have finite domains.
So our domains are going to be of some
size d, and we'll generally just kind
of write d to indicate the size of a
typical domain, or the maximum domain
in a problem.
That means that if you've got n
variables of domain size d, there's d
to the n many complete assignments.
So as usual, the stuff we care about, if
done in the naieve, exhaustive way
would be exponential.
Examples of these finite domain discrete
cases are things like Boolean
constraint satisfaction problems,
and that includes in
particular satisfy ability.
We know that's mp complete, so yet more
evidence that this is going to be
hard in the worst case.
There are also cases where you
have infinite domains, but
things are still discreet.
So for example, if there are string
value variables, and so on.
There are also continuous CSPs.
So for example, if you want to
have a start and end time
expressed as a real number.
We're going to focus
on the case up top.
In addition to having different
varieties of CSPs, we also have
different varieties of constraints.
So we've already talked about binary
constraints, which are constraints
between two variables.
So for example, that two countries
have to have a different color.
We can have unary constraints, which
involve just a single variable.
So we might say, for example, South
Australia needs to be green, or it
can't be green.
And if we say South Australia can't be
green, that's really just the same as
reducing its domain.
So we often don't talk much about unary
constraints, because they're
basically the same as just shrinking
the domains before you even start.
And then of course we can have
higher order constraints.
We've already seen constraints involving
three or more variables,
like in the crypt arithmetic case.
In addition to having constraints that
say things like these two countries
cannot have the same color, we could
imagine having soft constraints.
And these would be preferences, like all
else equal I'd rather use red than
green in my coloring.
And we might represent this as
some kind of cost function.
In that case, we don't really
have a CSP anymore.
Now we've got some kind of generalized
constrained optimization problem, and
we're not going to talk about
constraints at all until we get the
Bayes' nets much later.